I didn't ask to show this
picture.  I think this picture is a little
disrespectful
.  I don't know what kind of glasses these are.  You're
looking at me here.
So, that's the
last time I talked about the
woman.
And those of you who are at home can
say that Babontache was a great
master.  He also wrote his
uchingaryn, who was his eyewitness.  He
did all the work, and he, like Roza and
Anatoly, is a great person to have around, and we really
need people who can
do it.  He spent many years of his life
assisting and
publishing the teachings of his teacher.  And Fabon
Carinche, he is
known for practicing bajieni.  He
wrote the most insightful, helpful
commentary on your gin.  I
have translated and I have somewhere between 20,000 and 30,000
pages of Diamond Way translations, but it is
not usually published in the
usual way.  You just give it to
your students.  And these translations are just
waiting for
you.  I've been working on
this for about 10 years, translating a lot. And his books are the
best on the diamond path.  They are the
best.  They are the best.  And we will
study them.  And you need to know your line of
succession.  If people ask,
you should know.  And the coolest thing, I'll
say the last thing now, we'll move on to an
angel and an angel and a demon.
Sorry, angel and demon always get
less
time.  There
are 12 magnificent houses in my Seramei monastery.  You have
five, of which there are 12.
And there are
12 before that, which have existed for more than 50 years.  And
my teacher, he's into
that,
you know, and
basically there's also a kind of
tradition at
home, depending on which
state you come from.  For example, I'm from
Arizona.  And when I come to Christon,
we meet up with other friends and we
do something fun together there.  And that's really
cool, that's really close.  We became very close
to each other.  And
because it was in another
state, we didn't know all the news.
It was very difficult to
empathize with them, with people from
New York.  They speak with a New York
accent.  It is very difficult to deal with them.
And you have
where people are from your own state.  And
people usually travel thousands of places to
come and study in those
three huge monasteries.  And there is such a
house Dilron and it means eastern Tibet,
Chindu, Chindu district.  And they even have their own
dialect and language.  But other people,
they can't come there.
For example, if you're a white man and you're the first
white man, the first white guy in 600
years, then there's no Arizona house there.  And
they'll say, "Well, you can leave
home and go to
Diro and join them."  And what I want to
say is that this domrom, it would be the
best, then
torture, and it was also from this house.  And he is the
greatest
teacher, the greatest teacher is
Pavlonkarinche.  My teacher Boncarinche,
they came from this house of Denrom.  And if
your teachers come from that house of Glron,
then you also come from the house of Glron.  You
are also in the house of stairs where you
are, but you are also students of the house of
Muron.  You should be happy.  This is
very cool.  People will ask, "Are
you a Witness?"  And you say: "I am Belarusian at home."  What is this
?  And this is simply the
most wonderful writer in the history of
Kovonka.  He bakes, for example, he left
home in 1941 and he
was reborn
and his
reincarnation, he completed his
best works.  And then he died.  And then he was
reborn.  And this young Pabon Vinchev,
he was with me and studied with me
in my classes.  And I took his
biggest course.  And it was
wiretapping.  He is a great teacher and now he
teaches all over the world.
And this is at
the beginning of the years on the
path, at the beginning of the diamond
path.  In order to prepare for
this path, we need to study the line of
transmission, the line of succession of our
teachers.  I want to say that I
don't care where they came from.
I have no affection for a good country.
To be honest, I'm not a big
fan of many Pes cultures and
traditions, by the way.  Something is not something that interests me very much
.
For example, if I need to sing something
to you, when she sings like that, it
sounds a little like an opera.  They
sing like that and I'm like, "Oh, and I'm not
attached to American culture.
I'm probably the smallest
American you've ever met. I'm not
attached to any particular culture or anything
. I don't want to sell you
China or Japan. Well, I just feel like
we're one
country. And that's how I feel. And so
I'm not trying to sell you Tibet reading
or anything. It's just a way of
thinking, of living your life. And in
every country there are people who follow
that path. And in every country there are people
who don't follow that. And the people who
follow that, they're all in
one country. This is the country of Laurits. That's how I
see it. So I'm not trying to make you
wear these weird hats somewhere.
Ask me how many times I've worn my
hat
before, I've never once
said it was
n't acceptable in Pennsylvania. I
wore
it, and I wore mine once in New York.
do and change and they stopped me and
said: "What are you in Mossel?" And I'm like:
"Oh, you you
we I don't think that's possible.  What do you
wear if you have this
bell?" I don't think it's
very important for a person.
You dress like
your audience would. If you
go to a
business meeting to talk about business, you
drive a nice car, you wear a nice
jacket.
And if you're in Diamond Mountain, you
wear your regular clothes. That's
the rub. And so I'm not trying to
sell you something that's related to culture.
It's not a culture, it's a way of thinking. The
Diamond Way is a way of thinking. And in
this text
we're talking about teachers. And I want to
show you
a person who is successfully bowing down to
something. Here's Victorina.
So, our
company, it
exploded, it was
constantly increasing its turnover. Was it a
coincidence? I needed employees by
name. I made an ad. Maybe you
know someone, someone who knows a little bit about them about
anniversary
products. And we were just working a bunch of
hours. And then I, uh,
hired a woman from Barbanos. And she was really, really
high. And he said, "I
know you." I said, "Please
invite me." And then two people came. And
one person was a umaturma. And she needed a
job. She wasn't
famous at the time. She wasn't in any
movies at the time. And I interviewed her. And I
said, "Do you really want to be a
secretary for a diamond company?" She
said, "No." And I asked her, "What do you
really want to do?" And she said, "I want
to be an actress." I said, "Listen, I'm
not going to, uh, hire you.  Go and
get up, act." And I think
two months later she got some kind of role in a
movie. And
then she was, by
the way, on the
cover of the blockbuster more often than any other
woman, and her brother was grateful that
I didn't hire her. And then
this woman came, I had already hired her
. Such a tall woman. She had a
talent for jewelry.
And we worked very, very hard. I
said then: "We have a lot of work.
If you get this job, then you'll have to
work
a lot." And she says: "No, I don't
work like that." And I tell her: "I'm very
lazy in a big
company." And this is Dina says: "No, I do
n't do that." I ask her: "Why did you
come here then?" And she says: "No, no,
work."
And I'm
like this, suddenly such a word came out of
the gate. I'm like this,
she was, of course, very
problematic, but she
grew up in the company
where she worked in a big jubilee
company. There
was such an account
not good. Once I spent the night in
New York, because I needed to
open a safe. And some people only
knew the code from the safe. And I
spent the night once a week. And then I
started teaching people in my hotel, in a
room. I stood, sat behind the curtain. They
sat on the bed and more and
more people came and they all tried to
stop.  And then she says, "Can I
come to your class?" And I tell you,
"You won't like the water." And she's
like, "Well, I'll try." I
came like that. And I really liked it. She
studied, studied, studied. And
then she became a
nun. And the teacher ordained her
a nun.
And we started to
shine together. When was that? 30 years
ago. And then she came to Daimon
Mausi, did a three-year retreat here.
She helped
build. We
built this house together with our own
hands. And all the students carried the
whole thing themselves. It changed so much, I've never seen
anyone change so much. She
was a very difficult child. Not like that. And
then she suddenly became such a happy
person. And then we had the chance to do a
second three-year retreat. And she's like, "Oh, I
want to go there and she's the only one."
who
did a dimensional retreat twice. She
did a retreat together. And she's
incredible. And no one  didn't know she
had cancer all along. And she had cancer
even when I
met her. And we didn't tell anyone about it.
And she had really bad cancer, but she
just kept going.
[music]
went and
you know, people are doing such good
[ __ ], but to me if you want to
do [ __ ] with a temple, you just
get up and start building this temple
and do something. do something
to
help. And it's all good. These
incredible people, they hand me
red envelopes. Oh, we love you. And I'm like,
"Oh, I have a shovel.  They do
n't do that."
And I
think when you do the prostration,
you bow down to that, all the
transmission lines
go through that kind of prostration. It's a very
difficult job to build a city like this. It's
20 years of such difficult work. These
young Chinese friends, they say, "We're
doing the same thing." And we're like, "Yeah,
sure." I
said, "Shall we try?" Let them
try. She's like, "Okay, let her
try, it's difficult and it makes you
stronger.  If you want to do the
wiping for your llamas, if you want to
respect them, then just clean the
toilets.  And this is a real expansion.
is:
"Oh, that's easy. Such things are very easy,
namely the hard, hard work of
composition. I'll talk a little more now and
then questions and
answers. We'll do a question and
answer session, especially about the diamond path.
But I can take any questions.
You must have questions, for example, how
to continue with my diamond practice. And
lastly, this is an unusual part in
Gipson's book,
where they
say if you
recite the lamrin, then you have
vegetables. And this is the next picture. And this is a
famous chant, I
think it's in
Nepal. And some
say that the Lord Buddha was
born there. This is an unusual stupa, because it has
these big eyes. And these are the eyes of the Buddha. And
this is part of a great great stupa.
And when we left, finished this
stupa, Wus said, "This is some very
small stupa." And we say, "What do you
mean?  This is
pure, pure
marble." He says, "Let's make it like this
, like this big, like a two-story
building." And by the way, we
need to consider this view.
We can
destroy this desert. We don't
feel like we can put big
statues. They have to
blend into the landscape. We don't want
to disrupt this space. We want to
make it dull, calm. And that's why the eyes are
very important. You told Jetz Kapi that if
you study the Laman, you will get
eyes to actually see the
world. He got upset. He said, "This
book is not about that, so what is it about then?  And
lamrim is the eyes.  It's not that you
study
the lamrim, and you have vegetables." And
he said that the lari lamrin are the eyes.
If you
study the eyes, then you have the lamrin, you have
eyes. For what? In order to see
these hidden, hidden messages.
Because for the diamond path, by the way, the auton
Lama, he said that Tsungkhapa said,
told the story about Tsungkhapa and
his eyes. And I checked
where in the database of John Brady's contributions. I
checked there and found it on the last
page of the
Lamrimchimo. It's thousands of pages of the
Lamrimchimo. And it talks about
the eyes. It says that the lamrim is the
eyes. If you have the lamrim, then you have
eyes. And if you don't have the lamrim, then
you don't have eyes. What does that mean for us?
There's a
very, very famous
quote from Lord Buddha. And someone
asked me which meditation is the best?
And he's like, "What do you have on  mind?  And there
was such a big gap there for 2,000
years.  And it's better for you to put your left foot on top
or your right foot on top.  You
cross your right leg first and
then your left or left leg first.  There
is a big debate, a big controversy about this.  And
someone asked him, what pose, what's
your
favorite meditation pose?  And he said: "
I have
three of them."  Lord Buddha said, "I have three. I
meditate on a flat surface on my
bed. I meditate on when I sit on the
floor and I meditate when I'm arguing all of that.
So I want to suggest to you that
classical classical Lord Buddha said that there are
three types of times when you can
focus on the museum of meditation.
When you're running, sitting or standing,
you know,
always. Don't think there's any
other way. Maybe when you're
flying, maybe when you're walking, but in
any case I suggest ether until
we meet again in the lexicon with you.
Will you come to Live or Aline?
I
suggest that we have
, that we all
try, when we travel, or
go somewhere, or go in a car. When
you go
somewhere, especially going downstairs, for example, with
your other with your son, well,
somewhere and or in a car.
Once  you are moving to
get somewhere, to go, to
drive in a car or fly in a
plane, I would like to agree with you with
all
ours. We are all a small group of
diamond path, including online friends
and contacts, which will be on June 18. So, for
four
days before
that, while you are traveling, let's
agree that you will look for all
kinds of messages. You can sleep in
your bed, you don't need to look for
the remembered ones then. You can sit at a
table. You don't need to look for
the message either. And let's all
agree. I suggest that we
look for
messages when you are traveling in a
car or walking around the city or
flying in a plane. Agreement. I
think that only three people are
left now. That is, remember what your
homework is, what your work in the
diamond path is. I
will continue and I need to see if there are
any messages that have
been sent to me. For example, I
get a lot of different messages on the plane.
I fly a lot and I often  I keep my
ears open and someone is giving me
a message. I remember this
woman who was on her phone all the way
to Japan. And how many hours was it
? 11 hours.
I think she was sitting there like that for about 10 hours
. I was kind of
freaked out by that. I don't know what
anyone would be looking at their phone all the way
to Japan. And then I was
curious about what a person could be looking at for
11 hours. And when you go to the bathroom, you're
looking at other people. And I
looked when I went to the bathroom. I was just
curious about what
website she was looking at, what website
she was on and she found out that you could
turn on the camera and look at
yourself. Hey,
Shakeel. She was checking her makeup for 11
hours. And I was like, "Wow!  She's putting on
her makeup for 11
hours." I'm such a better person, I
don't even know how to do it. And it
makes me a better person. I would never
think about myself for that long, 11
hours. And then I'm like,
"Oh, this is a message, she's giving me
some kind of message that I'm thinking about
myself."
11 hours. Maybe she's a vajra yaginya, or
maybe she's An, or maybe
she's
afiti this. Maybe if I
had understood it earlier, she could have fallen asleep by now, and
she had to do 11.
God, this guy is so stupid, he doesn't
understand. Let's go on, let's go on.
So don't read, this is your homework.
This is what I want us to
do together, as a group, as a team. And you
travel, looking for all kinds of
messages. They can be
unusual, they can be strange.
What's the message when a scorpion climbs on your
leg like a
janchi? We're looking for these
messages. And if I ask, what's the
best practice of the diamond
path?  This is just a practice to
look for hidden messages.
Is there a message and what does it want
to convey to me, if it is, what is it
conveying to me, what message. I can't
say that it is not a bud. And
I can't say that it is not not
. I can't say that
it is a bud. I can't say for sure
that it wasn't this state of
doubt. I can't know for sure what it
was. Or I can't know for sure that it
wasn't. will be. And this middle,
the middle of doubt - this is very strong karma.
This is one of the strongest karmas that can
be. If you want financial freedom,
and if you want $ 100, then you can't
throw yourself at people. You have to be
happy, so that you have a
wonderful husband or wife. This is
wonderful karma. And you get everything you
dream of. And it's very unusual. And it's
very strange. These doubts, this is the
strongest karma that there is. And it's this this
Karma creates very strange things.
For example, a very successful life, a very
happy life. And it's cheap, it
costs nothing. It costs nothing to be
paranoid about this little thing. It costs nothing
. No effort at all.
Just 10 seconds on the way to the toilet and yet
another message. Hello. Well,
bye and let's go to the
toilet. We had an interesting Berlin from
China. By the way, about
toilets. I won't laugh at my
friends who had diarrhea. Hers was at the
same time. And also the company on the plane
closed the
toilets.
Okay, but this is a good way to lose
extra pounds. Let's do a session,
questions and answers. Do you have
homework? I have my homework.
Someday we will finish the demons with those too.
Hell, who will choose? Choose them. Who
will ask
the question? And by the way, after class I
need to
go quickly. There is a whole laboratory waiting for
me. Poem,  thank you for this class. I'm
curious about what
the message is here and now, when we're
hired to see Scorpio. By the way, I want to
say something about that. I think what I want to
say is that the messages are tailored to you
. They're sent to you personally
. I think that's part of
this practice. It's not that Desha Michael
decides what the message is. It's you
deciding what the message is for you. I
don't know what's going on in your life.
I have a lot of students. I don't know.
I don't know what's going on in their
lives. Do you know what's going on in
their lives? And the only thing I want to
say about these messages is that they're
designed to be delivered to you personally
. These two, these two people
can get two completely different
messages from the same event,
for example, Scorpio. And they'll both be
true, even though they're two
opposite, uh, messages. And that's a really
cool thing about the
messages. And another thing about the diamond
path is that everything that's
going on is your personal
messages. They're for you personally. And
You can take it and
use it. And this is the Diamond Way.
You asked me to teach the Diamond Way,
and I am teaching you the Diamond Way. Okay.
Next
question. Oh, what a nice cup.
Oh, you
[music]
really. Leader of
Malaysia. Thank you.
You can ask the question
Chinese Diamond is that it allows us to see many incredible impossible things, for example, yesterday the teacher said that in the Diamond Way education you can visualize yourself as a
Buddha, but my logic tells me that this is absolutely impossible, because I am not a Buddha, not a Buddha, so how can I apply these Diamond teachings to help me improve now or how can I understand these contents
for the
very hold on to your teachings for these two days. It
seems to me that the way has been learned. It is
very much that needs to be visualized
. Logically for me it is very much like that I have
problems seeing myself if
we can do this in the practice of the Diamond
Way, that this visualization works for
me.  I can start doing the practice
to bring the diamond
path into my life. Excellent question.
Thank you. What Bro John Brady did in
his
database. I don't know. I think we
plan to restore 300,000 books.
He only completed
3-4% somewhere. 100, 200-300 years eight to
complete. That's how much he still has to be
with us. And it's
incredible. It's 300,000
books. And the Western
classics, on which all
these Western universities are based, only 500 books
in them. For example, Harvard University.
They have a classical library of only 500 books
of aboca. There are 300,000 books and they are very high
quality. These are not just some stupid
books. These are not just Samaritan books.
Volodin's books. And there, for example, there are books,
for example, When a Man Pities
His Horse, and these books, each of them can
lead you to
enlightenment. You heard yesterday about the sutras
and shastras, right?
there are
990 sutras and tandras
left out of many thousands and
590 sutras
and excuse me shastras
left out and 85,000 commentaries that
were written later and the ancients divided
all these books into 12
categories Kanyur.
In this
klucciy, 990 books, and in Tengyur there are 14
sections of divisions.
John Freddie's spread there are about a thousand
different
sections, subdivisions and they
are cataloged. And it took more than
30 years. This
work is about 1000 categories. Why am I
talking about this? Because there are
tankas in this database. And vajragni is
one of the
stanstri second mitapka third and there are 160. In
John Brady's project they identified
160 different tan tantric systems.
Each of them is thousands of books and so it's
incredible. And each of them, for example,
vajara yuginya is divided into many
categories. As  to do retreats, how
to meditate, how to die, how
to teach this, how to do
initiations, many, many
different things. And then I asked my
teacher. I asked, "Do you teach us two by
two or three
traditions?" And we get the yamantika.
We have vaja yakni, actually two, and there are 160 of them.
And all my friends who studied with other teachers
, they have 10, 12, 50, and we
only have
two. I was kind of irritated about this
, and he
said, "That's all we practice in the
tantric monastery.
And the highest practices in the highest practices
there
are thousands of monasteries, of which only two are
monasteries there.  That's all we're
learning.  We study two.  I'm like, "Wow!
Why is that? Why do all these other tantors
exist?"  And he said, "Well, everyone is different,
because everyone needs different
teachings. That's why there are five houses."
Everyone is attracted to different things
.  This is the story of Veronica in the
cowboy store where
my
wife tried on 42 pairs of jeans.  And I
was counting, I was standing, there was no chair here, I was
irritated by this.  And she didn't buy any
of them.  Never tell this
story.  And this means that different people
need different
things.  There, for example, are 160
different pairs of clothes.  I think that there are actually
thousands, those that are preserved in the database, yes, there are
more of them, but those that are preserved in the database are
data about Nabre and there are 160 of them. And you came to
this thunder.  And if you tell me, or you
tell your teacher: "You know,
something about me doesn't go well with the
Yamanka,
or let's be honest, I don't
go well with it either. It's strange and it's a
little
scary."  I'm
like, "Is there any other choice?"  And my
teacher says: "It seems to me that you are a
free spirited person."  I am
such a
teacher, his
approach, his approach was his tradition, an ancient
tradition that is 2000 years old.  That is, we
basically give several choices.  You can
be so strong or you can
be such a nice, beautiful
angel.  Personally, I like
this beautiful angel and I connect with
him.  And when you study diamond n you
teacher should be way several options.
Basically, we give you diamantika and
badjaeginya.  You don't need to
know anything about it.  Just enjoy these
diamond path activities, and the options
are waiting, we have them.  And if it doesn't
feel like something for you
right away, don't worry about it.  You
will change or we
will offer to
dissuade you.
In the end, they are all the same.  This is how
Lord Buddha looks like a variety of
jeans.  It's just one person looking
like 160 different types of jeans.  But
in the end, it's still the same person.  And I
believe what I used to
think, you can go with the practice,
wanting, if you
feel that you are more attracted to a woman,
that this woman will be, and if you want directly
as authoritarian as the president that
we
know, whose name we can
pronounce, then you
can.  It depends on who you
feel more comfortable with.  What's cool about
the practice of the Diamond Way is that there is so
much waiting for you.
If you don't immediately feel like it's right for
you, then go to someone else.  Who is
more suitable?  We have others if you
want, but I want to offer you another one guys
.  I think I've
told you about five other big
topics before.  Abhidharma, Vinaya
logic.  Middle Way Lower School and
Middle Way Upper School.  And
only consciousness is there somewhere.  When I
was in Hershey's course, when I got
to logic, I hated it.  I really,
really hate her.  And I'm like, "Oh, I can't
, I'm leaving, I'm leaving soon
."  And I'm not interested in it
[music] at all
, like the dens at this school.  This is
all that is not very good for me.  And
the teacher could speak English then.
He's
like, I'm like, "Oh, I don't understand a thing
you're saying." And he was trying
to explain to me these terms of logic in
extraordinary English. And that was even worse
. I mean, I've told this story
many times. I went
from my room to his
room. He had just given me a lesson
on flooring.
I was sleeping on the floor of the garage, on the cement
floor in a
sleeping bag. This was my room. I did
n't have much money to have a
place to sleep. And I was sleeping on the floor of the
garage
with this
local drunk who was hiding in this
garage. And I was always afraid that he
might kill me. And I was walking, I remember
stopping under a tree. I was devastated.
I'm like, "I don't know if I can
keep doing this, if I can even
learn this." Then this voice came to me all
of a sudden and it
said, "You'll learn, you'll
be able to learn.  There is something important there.  There
is something you can do.  So
replace it and learn from it.  become a
master of it.  Wow, I got a
message.  And this moment, under this
tree, you can still see this
tree.  And I said to myself, "I'll
do it."  This is the thing I
dislike the most.  This is the only subject that
I don't like at all.  At
some point I got this message
that you have to do this.  You have to do what
you dislike the most,
because you don't have that practice yet.
You
need practice.  This practice that you
dislike the most is the one that is
missing within you.  And this is a very
interesting idea.
You can
wait, so you have different traditions.  John,
Breby and Connie will give you other
lineages, other traditions.  You
will have a choice in this.  You can
wait for what suits your
unusual copy.  You can
wait, but you still have other options.  that
maybe those who don't
attract you aren't interesting to you, maybe that's what
you're
missing.  When I became a good
blocker then, I became the
best.  And this is a very complex subject.  I was
literally dying over this logic.
Now I know, and it's incredible.  This is the
most important and valuable thing.  So don't
always think that the thing that is comfortable
for you is the right thing, the right thing
for you.  Maybe the one that doesn't
appeal to you.  This is what you lack, what
you need.  And so
sometimes force yourself to do things that don't
excite you.  If you do what
fascinates you, what attracts you, then you will
not learn anything new.   Do
you understand?  Don't forget about it.  Rad,
how much time do we have
?  Thank you very much, Kishala, for your teaching
today.  Yesterday, while I was
reading Loda John Cap's book, I thought
about the little bird, about Calibri.  And she
flew to me while I was reading.  I was
so happy.  I shared my
karmic partner, my roommate.  And
the next day she also arrived.  And I
moved and they told me that it was a sign of
easy
enlightenment, like an easy path to
enlightenment.
And I really
like it.  The question then is that yesterday I
saw this good
sign.  If we see that everything comes from
our karma and, for example, I see a bad
sign, then what do I need to do?  Four
forces.  Thank you.  Good question.
Something is wrong.  I'm trying
to remember now.  Yes, he said.  Here is
the answer.  I lived with my
mother.  I was his
driver.  I was a yogi
, a
karma.
He was mowing the paths.  And when you serve a
lama, you hear everything they say.  It's a
dirty job for 25 years, but
you learn a lot because you're always with
him, what they say to other people, you
hear it.  And this is what he said one
time.  I once
said, he said: "Oh, it's
burning sometimes I have such beautiful signs,
I have beautiful dreams. I see these
beautiful signs in them. And there the sky seems to
open. And I see how the tsnkapa
comes out of the sky.
And I have these beautiful
dreams I want to tell you first of all what it
means, how to interpret these dreams. And
then I have horrors
and some terrible things come to me in
dreams.
It seems like these are bad signs. I don't
know how to read these signs. And I want to
ask your advice. And here's his opinion.
He said that in the diamond path, when
you have a beautiful dream and something beautiful
happens, for example, you meet a
bodhi or you fly in your dream, or
maybe you become a woman whose bodhi or
something like that, then this is a true sign. This is a
true sign that you are making
progress.
When calibers fly to you, you
feel that it will lead you to
enlightenment. This is a good sign. This  a sign
that your practice is going well. And he
said,
"Congratulations." I thought it was strange to congratulate
a person with his. I was like, "Congratulations." And
then the person said, "What about the
bad news, the bad news?" And he
said, "You must have eaten something bad
after
dinner." Maybe you ate old pizza
. What were you doing there, I don't
remember? Maybe you ate bad pizza?
And then he
said, "That's
how true these bad
reports are.  And sorry, he said a
bad word.  If you have a bad
message,
for example, uh, the sun is blocking it and it's
getting dark, and you can say, "That must
have been a bad lunch."  Turn to
this.  Don't take this to heart.  You'll
just think, "Well, I just
ate something wrong, well, something like that."  And you
must have eaten something wrong, you have
gas in your lungs.  It's like a bad dream.  It's like
these gases are escaping.  And his advice
was to just pay attention to the
good visions and think a lot about
thinking about them.  And when something bad
comes, don't give them that honor.
Give them that respect and say, "Go
away, go away, I don't even think about you
."  Some scorpion is coming.  Well,
let it be.
OK.  Yes.  And I really like it.
I like this tradition.  I
think we have another question.  Time for
one more question.
love of
the dead of the night
we send one question and they say:
"Hello,
children, grandfather. That's it, don't answer,
don't know.
Earlier you said that someone has to
complete the course before going to the
diamond path. What seeds are needed in order to
receive the diamond path? In order
not to go to the Gesh teachings. And how do we
need to continue to
reinvest these seeds?
Once. My point is that
if you complete the 18 courses and you then
go to the diamond path, 18 courses,
complete, well, 18 courses, then your
practice will be more skillful and clearer.
And the teachers about what we are talking about now,
these teachers are
not enough in our world. There is a great
shortage of such teachers. And I want to
say that imagine, New York, New York
or Singapore only produces two doctors. And
in fact, it is. And
I have a few people out of every
thousand who understand these things. Just a
few people who can
teach this.  So, all people are suffering and
there is a shortage of
doctors. And I
think we need to
do what we need to do to
create more doctors as much as possible in
this way and safely. That is, you don't
give
a person two weeks of training and don't
give a scalpel. Well, go ahead and do a
heart operation. Well, then you'll hurt someone. But
we don't have that much time. I don't know
how long you're going to live. I don't know
how long I'm going to live. We don't know which of
us is going to die first. And we need to
finish this now. And so we need to
take care of this now.
So I want to
say that there will be demands of the body. He
will tell people what it takes to
study the Diamond Way and
then teach others the Diamond Way. But
better, if you take 18 basic courses and 18
additional courses of the Diamond Additional
Courses ICI, you will be a better doctor. There is
this old type of doctor, what is called a
family doctor. I have a
woman like that, she is about
my age, they have stopped issuing them
in such  doctors. That's the general practitioner
. That's the kind of doctor you
go to and you say, "I have a
headache." And he says, "Oh, you need to
go to the doctor for a headache or
I have something with my toe." And
you need to go to other specialists and they keep
referring you to other specialists. And it's
very rare to find that
old-fashioned specialist, that
general practitioner, who knows all the
problems well enough.
I want to create these family
general practitioners. I want you to
be masters of different fields.
If someone asks you a question about bad
dreams or bad grades, you'll
have the answer right there and you won't have to
say, "Oh, go talk to Sophie in Tokyo
."
I don't know the answer. See what I
mean? And it seems like it's like doctors, it
seems like the best doctors,
they never stop teaching. You know, when
they're 60 years old, 70 years old. I say, "Can
I come to you next week?" And
he says,  "No, I'm going to continue my studies.  Well,
you're 60-70 years old.  Why is it quiet in
class?  Because I want to learn even
more.  And I want to help people even more
.  even more people.  And I
respect these kinds of doctors, and they
always learn something new, new techniques,
new practices.  My
wife had a knee replacement
.  And this doctor, he was performing
surgery with the help of a robot.  And there are 20
doctors who can do it with their own
hands.  And only one who can
do it with the help of a robot.  And the robot is
more precise, neater.  And after that
it heals faster.  And now he's fine
.  Even she doesn't
remember which knee the surgery was on.
Both knees function perfectly.  And
so this doctor, he's already a great surgeon,
he's already very famous and he can
operate on you very well.
But he continues to study robots and he
wants to treat them too.  And now you have a
choice.  Some complex operations need to
be done by hand, and most of them are
better done by robots.  And a robot doesn't make the
mistakes that humans do.  They
definitely are.  I think I like
doctors who know both.  And then
I can
get, I can understand which one is better
for me and I will get.  As a teacher, I don't
want you to come to me and say, should
I take 14 courses or 15?  I say,
"Take all of them, and then take them again
, then I'll take them a third time."
And don't ask, don't ask me those
irritating questions.
Do I need a 13 with a
prom, if I did, can I
teach?  Don't ask me to make such
decisions.  Study robots and learn
to do everything with your hands.  And once you
learn to help others, start
helping others.  You don't have to
wait until you become a
robot master.  You need to help people,
but harm them.  But if you give a
knife to a child and ask them to perform
heart surgery, then maybe I'll wait for someone
else.  Therefore, this is a delicate issue.  We don't
want to, we want people to not
cause harm and not make mistakes
when teaching, but at the same time we don't want to
wait until you have
50 years of experience because you will have
less time to help and you will help
fewer people.  So first of all,
I follow what Tim says.  And
secondly, you cannot stop in
your studies.  You should never
stop.  You can study the path of the alas for
100 lifetimes, but you can never
become a master, because it is infinite.
But whenever you can, do sports
in order to learn the most, in order to
help a large number of
people.  If you need to know about
the courses, how many there are, talk to the house.
Thank you.
If it were me and John Freddy and Connie and
Ellie, they would be giving
courses.  Both Peter and
Maria are learning the diamond path.  If
this, well,